<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Law and Language | University of Western Ontario</title>
    <link>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Law and Language | University of Western Ontario</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.136.5</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 10:54:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About the project</title>
      <link>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 10:54:39 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our project brings together scholars from Law, Political Science, Philosophy and French Studies at the University of Western Ontario to investigate how laws are interpreted within legal institutions and understood by the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all language, the language of law can be ambiguous, vague, or otherwise hard to understand. It often combines technical and ordinary meanings, aiming to be precise, but also accessible to everyone. As a result, the intention of the legislature can be unclear. This poses problems both for judges interpreting the law and for people trying to follow it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meaning</title>
      <link>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/posts/meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/posts/meaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fiction-meaning-and-interpretation&#34;&gt;Fiction, meaning and interpretation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said earlier that legal fictions allow us to modify the reach of the law in particular cases or kinds of case without reinterpreting legal terms. This is one valuable feature of legal fictions brought out by my account. In this section, I’ll elaborate on this point by contrasting legal fictions with an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic problem addressed by legal fictions is this. There is a legal rule that attaches consequences to falling under a certain word, like ‘clergyman’ or ‘dependant.’ In some kinds of case, there are reasons why the consequences should apply even though the word’s requirements are not satisfied, or the consequences should not apply even though the word’s requirements are satisfied. Legal fictions allow us to arrive at the right result without revising the legal rule. Of course, wherever there is a reason to use a legal fiction, there is also a reason to revise the legal rule. So, the technique of legal fictions is particularly useful where there are constraints on our ability to revise the legal rule.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal fictions</title>
      <link>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/posts/testblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://merryxmasfromhegel.github.io/law-language/posts/testblog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perpetual injunction to restrain proceedings against a Dane, for tlie seizure of property of English subjects in Iceland, the seizure being sanctionsd by the Danish, authorities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of Peter Blad, a subject of Denmark, against Bamfield and Others, came now to be heard (of which see the beginning before at the council board (see the preceding case), and the scope of the suit was to stay several actions commenced at law in trespass and trover, for seizing certain goods of the Defendants for trading in Iceland, contrary to certain privileges claimed there by the Plaintiff and others. The Defendants insisted that tins was no cause of state, and was ergo dismissed from the council table; that the injuries they had suffered were great, and such as were done with gome kind of affront to and contempt of the English nation ; that they had a most undoubted right of trade in Iceland, and by the articles of peace with Denmark, were to use their commerce with the subjects of Denmark without molestation ; that if the King of Denmark had granted any patents of privilege contrary to the freedom of trade, they were illegal, and a breach of the treaty in question ; and if the patents were of ancienter date, they had been dispensed with by the contrary practice, which had suffered English to trade there, and so invited the Defendants ; that, however, the Plaintiff had already had all the benefit of this Court which he could reasonably expect, for he obtained an injunction till he had examined his witnesses, and now having perfected his proofs, whatever could avail him here, would also avail him at law ; wherefore they prayed leave, that now, at last, they might go to their trial at law.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
